<flashcards>
    <flashcard>
        <question><![CDATA[Define Euclidean domain.]]></question>
        <answer><![CDATA[
            A Euclidean domain is an integral domain \( D \) equipped with a degree function \( d: D \setminus \{0\} \to \mathbb{N} \) such that for any nonzero elements \( a \) and \( b \) in \( D \), there exist elements \( q \) and \( r \) in \( D \) such that \( a = bq + r \) with \( r = 0 \) or \( d(r) < d(b) \).
        ]]></answer>
    </flashcard>
    <flashcard>
        <question><![CDATA[State the Division Algorithm in a Euclidean domain.]]></question>
        <answer><![CDATA[
            The Division Algorithm in a Euclidean domain states that for any nonzero elements \( a \) and \( b \) in the Euclidean domain \( D \), there exist elements \( q \) and \( r \) in \( D \) such that \( a = bq + r \) with \( r = 0 \) or \( d(r) < d(b) \), where \( d \) is the degree function of \( D \).
        ]]></answer>
    </flashcard>
    <flashcard>
        <question><![CDATA[Define principal ideal domain (PID).]]></question>
        <answer><![CDATA[
            A principal ideal domain (PID) is an integral domain \( D \) in which every ideal is principal, i.e., every ideal of \( D \) can be generated by a single element.
        ]]></answer>
    </flashcard>
    <flashcard>
        <question><![CDATA[State the Euclidean Algorithm in a Euclidean domain.]]></question>
        <answer><![CDATA[
            The Euclidean Algorithm in a Euclidean domain \( D \) allows us to find the greatest common divisor (GCD) of two nonzero elements \( a \) and \( b \). It repeatedly applies the Division Algorithm to find a sequence of remainders until reaching a remainder of \( 0 \), and the last nonzero remainder obtained is the GCD of \( a \) and \( b \).
        ]]></answer>
    </flashcard>
    <flashcard>
        <question><![CDATA[Define unique factorization domain (UFD).]]></question>
        <answer><![CDATA[
            A unique factorization domain (UFD) is an integral domain \( D \) in which every nonzero non-unit element can be uniquely factored as a product of irreducible elements (up to associates), and this factorization is unique up to the order of the factors.
        ]]></answer>
    </flashcard>
    <flashcard>
        <question><![CDATA[State the Fundamental Theorem of Arithmetic in a unique factorization domain.]]></question>
        <answer><![CDATA[
            The Fundamental Theorem of Arithmetic in a unique factorization domain states that every nonzero non-unit element can be expressed as a product of irreducible elements (up to associates) in a unique way, up to the order of the factors.
        ]]></answer>
    </flashcard>
    <flashcard>
        <question><![CDATA[Prove that every Euclidean domain is a principal ideal domain (PID).]]></question>
        <answer><![CDATA[
        Let \( D \) be a Euclidean domain. To prove that \( D \) is a PID, we need to show that every ideal of \( D \) is principal.

        Let \( I \) be an ideal of \( D \). If \( I = \{0\} \), then \( I \) is the zero ideal and is generated by \( 0 \). Assume \( I \neq \{0\} \). Choose any nonzero element \( b \) in \( I \) with the smallest degree among all nonzero elements in \( I \). We claim that \( I = (b) \), i.e., \( I \) is generated by \( b \).

        Let \( a \) be any element in \( I \). By the Division Algorithm, we can write \( a = bq + r \) with \( r = 0 \) or \( d(r) < d(b) \). Since \( r = a - bq \) is in \( I \) and \( b \) has the smallest degree among all nonzero elements in \( I \), it follows that \( r = 0 \). Therefore, \( a = bq \), showing that \( a \) is in the ideal generated by \( b \). Thus, \( I \subseteq (b) \).

        On the other hand, since \( b \) is in \( I \), it is clear that \( (b) \subseteq I \). Hence, \( I = (b) \), and we conclude that every ideal of \( D \) is principal. Therefore, \( D \) is a PID.
        (Dummit and Foote, Section 8.2, Theorem 1)
    ]]></answer>
    </flashcard>
</flashcards>